<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell on Adam Cook</title>
    <link>https://adamcook.io/categories/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell on Adam Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamcook.io/categories/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Powershell Code Into Production Using Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in the week I presented at a WinAdmins virtual user group session. At the bottom of this post you can watch the recording.
The session covered the below topics:
 Introduction to CI/CD pipeline, i.e. what it means with practical explanations A walk through on the YAML structure/syntax of GitHub Actions Demonstrate on how to use Actions by uploading content to Azure Blob storage Demonstrate a self hosted runner Demonstrate how to deploy a PowerShell module to: the PowerShell Gallery, create a new GitHub release, a shared folder within my home lab (which failed because I messed with the runner&amp;rsquo;s service log-on credential) and to a self hosted NuGet feed (which also failed, thanks demo gods)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get CMUnusedSources</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a PowerShell script that reports on what folders are used or unused by System Center Configuration Manager.
You can find it here on GitHub.
I demoed the script at the London Windows Manager User Group, you can watch the recording below on YouTube.
  Among a bunch of technical topics, I also learned a huge amount of valuable soft/personal things too.
Enough is enough I started writing in February and since then I have refactored the script and the idea itself many times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
