<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Adam Cook</title>
    <link>https://adamcook.io/categories/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Adam Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:29:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamcook.io/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell vs. CSharp Azure Functions Cold Starts</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/powershell-vs.-csharp-azure-functions-cold-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:29:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/powershell-vs.-csharp-azure-functions-cold-starts/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty committed to a new job I started at the start of the year. I need to find more positive outlets and return to doing the things I enjoy in my down-time. I hope to do more tinkering on side projects and giving back to the community.
The cover image for this post if for our pup, Alfie! He&amp;rsquo;s a beagle and we will be bringing him home in a couple of weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo Websites in Azure for Pennies or Free on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 21:04:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated my WordPress blogging platform to generating static content with Hugo. I no longer pay for hosting. I exclusively use GitHub Pages. I am now blogging at no extra cost other than domain renewal!
In the process not only did I learn about Hugo, but I also looked at three ways to deploy / host my Hugo-made website.
In this post I want to share with you what Hugo is, why I like it and those three ways that I learned on how to deploy a Hugo website - with Azure Static Web Apps (preview), Azure Blob storage and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dynamic Azure ARM Templates</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how you can dynamically create resources or set properties for resources in your Azure ARM templates.
For example, you might have a template which accepts an array. For each element in that array, you want to create resources, or set properties for a resource.
The first objective will demonstrate how to create a dynamic number of properties associated with a resource. The second object will show you how to dynamically create a number of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
