<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adam Cook</title>
    <link>https://adamcook.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adam Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamcook.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Powershell Code Into Production Using Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in the week I presented at a WinAdmins virtual user group session. At the bottom of this post you can watch the recording.
The session covered the below topics:
 Introduction to CI/CD pipeline, i.e. what it means with practical explanations A walk through on the YAML structure/syntax of GitHub Actions Demonstrate on how to use Actions by uploading content to Azure Blob storage Demonstrate a self hosted runner Demonstrate how to deploy a PowerShell module to: the PowerShell Gallery, create a new GitHub release, a shared folder within my home lab (which failed because I messed with the runner&amp;rsquo;s service log-on credential) and to a self hosted NuGet feed (which also failed, thanks demo gods)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo Websites in Azure for Pennies or Free on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 21:04:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated my WordPress blogging platform to generating static content with Hugo. I no longer pay for hosting. I exclusively use GitHub Pages. I am now blogging at no extra cost other than domain renewal!
In the process not only did I learn about Hugo, but I also looked at three ways to deploy / host my Hugo-made website.
In this post I want to share with you what Hugo is, why I like it and those three ways that I learned on how to deploy a Hugo website - with Azure Static Web Apps (preview), Azure Blob storage and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dynamic Azure ARM Templates</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how you can dynamically create resources or set properties for resources in your Azure ARM templates.
For example, you might have a template which accepts an array. For each element in that array, you want to create resources, or set properties for a resource.
The first objective will demonstrate how to create a dynamic number of properties associated with a resource. The second object will show you how to dynamically create a number of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get CMUnusedSources</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a PowerShell script that reports on what folders are used or unused by System Center Configuration Manager.
You can find it here on GitHub.
I demoed the script at the London Windows Manager User Group, you can watch the recording below on YouTube.
  Among a bunch of technical topics, I also learned a huge amount of valuable soft/personal things too.
Enough is enough I started writing in February and since then I have refactored the script and the idea itself many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr SQL Server Upgrade From 2012 SP4 to 2017 CU13</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</guid>
      <description>Currently my lab&amp;rsquo;s primary site is running on 2012 R2. I recently wanted to try LEDBAT so I could sell it to a customer but it needed to be on 2016 or newer. I could have configured a 2016 &amp;ldquo;source DP&amp;rdquo; using pull distribution points and still get the experience, but then I was curious if IPU while ConfigMgr is installed was possible, turns out it is. Then I discovered I had SQL 2012 SP2 installed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Throttling Distribution Point Bandwidth</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</guid>
      <description>ℹ️ It looks like as I was writing this Microsoft have just publicly released a former internal document detailing some things that I had claimed to be undocumented (click here): Deep, deep, DEEP dive into content distribution in #SCCM by the great @vinay_pamnani Internal-only content originally, now free for public use! https://t.co/oUPTSzrTmt
&amp;mdash; Matt Toto (@_contoto) February 4, 2019   In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover ways you can control bandwidth for Configuration Manager using the rate limit config available for each distribution point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Hardware Inventory Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated a site to 1806 and was keen to get all clients up to date too. Some machines targeted for the pre-production client were not upgrading. When I looked closer at one client I suspected client health because a hardware inventory had not been submitted in months.
Little did I know until recently, a lack of recent hardware inventory data could be a result of other things and client health is least likely to be the root cause.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
