<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adam Cook</title>
    <link>https://adamcook.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adam Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamcook.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using PowerShell to Manage Shlink With PSShlink</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/using-powershell-to-manage-shlink-with-psshlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/using-powershell-to-manage-shlink-with-psshlink/</guid>
      <description>Shlink is an open-source self-hosted and PHP-based URL shortener application. I wrote PSShlink which will help you manage all of your short codes using PowerShell!
Shlink helped me tremendously when I moved my domain and blog CMS from cookadam.co.uk to adamcook.io. Some of my posts rank modestly in search results for some keywords and I felt unhappy about letting that go. I also did not want people&amp;rsquo;s bookmarks for posts using my old domain to result in an incomplete redirect to its new URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting and Protecting Your Own NuGet Feed with ProGet</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/hosting-and-protecting-your-own-nuget-feed-with-proget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/hosting-and-protecting-your-own-nuget-feed-with-proget/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will share with you how to install Inedo&amp;rsquo;s ProGet to host your own NuGet feed (effectively your own PowerShell Gallery). This will let you share PowerShell modules and scripts amongst other systems and colleagues from an internal resource, using cmdlets from the PowerShellGet module e.g. Install-Module, Install-Script, Find-Module, Find-Script etc.
Why might you want to do this? Remember when PowerShell Gallery went down for a while in October?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Powershell Code Into Production Using Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/getting-your-powershell-code-into-production-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in the week I presented at a WinAdmins virtual user group session. At the bottom of this post you can watch the recording.
The session covered the below topics:
 Introduction to CI/CD pipeline, i.e. what it means with practical explanations A walk through on the YAML structure/syntax of GitHub Actions Demonstrate on how to use Actions by uploading content to Azure Blob storage Demonstrate a self hosted runner Demonstrate how to deploy a PowerShell module to: the PowerShell Gallery, create a new GitHub release, a shared folder within my home lab (which failed because I messed with the runner&amp;rsquo;s service log-on credential) and to a self hosted NuGet feed (which also failed, thanks demo gods)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo Websites in Azure for Pennies or Free on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 21:04:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/deploying-hugo-websites-in-azure-for-pennies-or-free-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated my WordPress blogging platform to generating static content with Hugo. I no longer pay for hosting. I exclusively use GitHub Pages. I am now blogging at no extra cost other than domain renewal!
In the process not only did I learn about Hugo, but I also looked at three ways to deploy / host my Hugo-made website.
In this post I want to share with you what Hugo is, why I like it and those three ways that I learned on how to deploy a Hugo website - with Azure Static Web Apps (preview), Azure Blob storage and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting to Automate Animated Content for Virtual Events</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/starting-to-automate-animated-content-for-virtual-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/starting-to-automate-animated-content-for-virtual-events/</guid>
      <description>I recently took ownership of becoming the organiser for my local PowerShell user group - PowerShell Southampton. With everything going on in the world re the pandemic, I realised I won&amp;rsquo;t be arranging in-person meetups any time soon.
I got stuck in and learnt ways I could produce a virtual event: looked at the tech available and weighed up the features, pros/cons etc with how I wanted it to look and what I wanted the user experience to be for all involved (organiser, speaker and audience).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dynamic Azure ARM Templates</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/creating-dynamic-azure-arm-templates/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how you can dynamically create resources or set properties for resources in your Azure ARM templates.
For example, you might have a template which accepts an array. For each element in that array, you want to create resources, or set properties for a resource.
The first objective will demonstrate how to create a dynamic number of properties associated with a resource. The second object will show you how to dynamically create a number of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr WSUS woes, WSUSCtrl.log &#34;Cannot open database &#34;SUSDB&#34; requested by the login. The login failed.~~Login failed for user &#39;DOMAIN\SERVER$&#39;&#34;</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-wsus-woes-wsusctrl.log-cannot-open-database-susdb-requested-by-the-login.-the-login-failed.~~login-failed-for-user-domain%5Cserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-wsus-woes-wsusctrl.log-cannot-open-database-susdb-requested-by-the-login.-the-login-failed.~~login-failed-for-user-domain%5Cserver/</guid>
      <description>First post as MEMCM rather than SCCM. I think since my last post in July I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a dozen unfinished drafts but you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having too much fun.. working.
I recently stood up a remote SUP with its own WSUS role and SQL database. What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise was, even though it was still syncing updates from the upstream SUP/WSUS server just fine, the status messages for the SMS_WSUS_CONTROL_MANAGER component on the new SUP/WSUS box was coughing up a bunch of errors ever since I installed the roles and configured them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Management Point 500.19 CcmMessaging.log 0x87d00231</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-management-point-500.19-ccmmessaging.log-0x87d00231/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-management-point-500.19-ccmmessaging.log-0x87d00231/</guid>
      <description>My lab recently started playing up when I noticed clients weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new policies.
TDLR (it&amp;rsquo;s not even that long!): a while ago I moved my SUP/WSUS off host from the site server that also hosted a MP. As a result it seemed to have triggered this known issue: Management points stop responding to HTTP requests with error 500.19.
First port of call was CcmMessaging.log to see it was at least talking to MP OK, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get CMUnusedSources</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a PowerShell script that reports on what folders are used or unused by System Center Configuration Manager.
You can find it here on GitHub.
I demoed the script at the London Windows Manager User Group, you can watch the recording below on YouTube.
  Among a bunch of technical topics, I also learned a huge amount of valuable soft/personal things too.
Enough is enough I started writing in February and since then I have refactored the script and the idea itself many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr SQL Server Upgrade From 2012 SP4 to 2017 CU13</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</guid>
      <description>Currently my lab&amp;rsquo;s primary site is running on 2012 R2. I recently wanted to try LEDBAT so I could sell it to a customer but it needed to be on 2016 or newer. I could have configured a 2016 &amp;ldquo;source DP&amp;rdquo; using pull distribution points and still get the experience, but then I was curious if IPU while ConfigMgr is installed was possible, turns out it is. Then I discovered I had SQL 2012 SP2 installed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to PHP 7.2 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/upgrading-to-php-7.2-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/upgrading-to-php-7.2-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I run LibreNMS in my homelab on a Ubuntu Server VM and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.
  
For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting notifications for needing to bump from PHP 7.0 to 7.2 minimum.
I mostly followed this post but I&amp;rsquo;ll detail a step that helped me automate installing and uninstalling all the extra modules which the last two steps seem to miss. I&amp;rsquo;ll also detail a snag I hit with nginx slapping me with 500 after updating to PHP 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpdatesDeployment.log Job Error (0x80004005)</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/updatesdeployment.log-job-error-0x80004005/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/updatesdeployment.log-job-error-0x80004005/</guid>
      <description>Glorious, 0x80004005.
No updates showing in Software Center? Is a client reporting in an unknown state in your reports?
Do you see this in UpdatesDeployment.log when triggering Software Update Deployment Evaluation Cycle?
Job error (0x80004005) received for assignment ({09985588-0eff-47e1-9f9d-3846efce8c2b}) action	Updates will not be made available Give this a whirl:
Move-Item -Path &amp;#34;$env:SystemRoot\System32\GroupPolicy\Machine\Registry.pol&amp;#34; -Destination &amp;#34;$env:SystemRoot\System32\GroupPolicy\Machine\Registry.pol.old&amp;#34; Invoke-GPUpdate -Force Verify a new Registry.pol file is created, then trigger Software Update Deployment Evaluation Cycle and Software Updates Scan Cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blank InstalledOn Property for Get-HotFix and Win32_QuickFixEngineering</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/blank-installedon-property-for-get-hotfix-and-win32_quickfixengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/blank-installedon-property-for-get-hotfix-and-win32_quickfixengineering/</guid>
      <description>Want to get Windows Update status on a bunch of machines, only to discover the InstalledOn property is blank for lots of updates when you&amp;rsquo;re using Get-HotFix or querying Win32_QuickFixEngineering class with Get-WmiObject?
Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s related to PowerShell parsing the date as string to datetime object incorrectly, depending what your system locale is.
$Updates = Get-HotFix | Select-Object description,hotfixid,installedby,@{l=&amp;#34;InstalledOn&amp;#34;;e={[DateTime]::Parse($_.psbase.properties[&amp;#34;installedon&amp;#34;].value,$([System.Globalization.CultureInfo]::GetCultureInfo(&amp;#34;en-US&amp;#34;)))}} $Updates | Sort InstalledOn -Descending | Select -First 10 I like the above approach, as posted by user pyro3113, because the select expression lets you easily query remote systems using Get-HotFix or Get-WmiObject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Throttling Distribution Point Bandwidth</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</guid>
      <description>ℹ️ It looks like as I was writing this Microsoft have just publicly released a former internal document detailing some things that I had claimed to be undocumented (click here): Deep, deep, DEEP dive into content distribution in #SCCM by the great @vinay_pamnani Internal-only content originally, now free for public use! https://t.co/oUPTSzrTmt
&amp;mdash; Matt Toto (@_contoto) February 4, 2019   In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover ways you can control bandwidth for Configuration Manager using the rate limit config available for each distribution point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Hardware Inventory Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated a site to 1806 and was keen to get all clients up to date too. Some machines targeted for the pre-production client were not upgrading. When I looked closer at one client I suspected client health because a hardware inventory had not been submitted in months.
Little did I know until recently, a lack of recent hardware inventory data could be a result of other things and client health is least likely to be the root cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compare DD-WRT WAN IP to a Host public IP</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/compare-dd-wrt-wan-ip-to-a-host-public-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/compare-dd-wrt-wan-ip-to-a-host-public-ip/</guid>
      <description>For my home lab on a particular VM that runs Ubuntu Server, I&amp;rsquo;m interested to know the public IP of my LAN&amp;rsquo;s gateway and the VM&amp;rsquo;s gateway (as it&amp;rsquo;s always connected to VPN). Below is a script I wrote to pull the WAN IP from my DD-WRT router and compare that to VM&amp;rsquo;s gateway public IP.
My copy does other things like start/stop services, configure local applications in my home lab as well as use Pushbullet to notify me if certain conditions are met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Database Move: Failed to Create/Backup SQL SSB Certificate</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-database-move-failed-to-create/backup-sql-ssb-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-database-move-failed-to-create/backup-sql-ssb-certificate/</guid>
      <description>In a recent project I had to move the SQL database for a single primary site hierarchy to a different host in order to go beyond version 1610, because support for Windows Server 2008 R2 had ended from 1702 onward.
Everything was going smoothly up until it came to modifying the SQL configuration of the site. I was getting slapped by ConfigMgrSetup.log with:
 Create_BackupSQLCert : SQL server failed to backup cert.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
