<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ConfigMgr on Adam Cook</title>
    <link>https://adamcook.io/categories/configmgr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ConfigMgr on Adam Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 10:22:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamcook.io/categories/configmgr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patching Snowflakes With ConfigMgr and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/patching-snowflakes-with-configmgr-and-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 10:22:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/patching-snowflakes-with-configmgr-and-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Do you have servers in your environment that require special or manual patching? Do you have non-redundant application servers that must have a co-ordinated patching routine? Wish you used ConfigMgr for these but haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out a way? Do you have spaghetti or unfinished code that attempts to orchestrate complicated patching cycles?  By &amp;ldquo;special patching&amp;rdquo;, I mean the customer or application owners are terrified of the word &amp;ldquo;patching&amp;rdquo; and demand it be performed manually on a handful of finicky application servers out of fear of downtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr WSUS woes, WSUSCtrl.log &#34;Cannot open database &#34;SUSDB&#34; requested by the login. The login failed.~~Login failed for user &#39;DOMAIN\SERVER$&#39;&#34;</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-wsus-woes-wsusctrl.log-cannot-open-database-susdb-requested-by-the-login.-the-login-failed.~~login-failed-for-user-domain%5Cserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-wsus-woes-wsusctrl.log-cannot-open-database-susdb-requested-by-the-login.-the-login-failed.~~login-failed-for-user-domain%5Cserver/</guid>
      <description>First post as MEMCM rather than SCCM. I think since my last post in July I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a dozen unfinished drafts but you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having too much fun.. working.
I recently stood up a remote SUP with its own WSUS role and SQL database. What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise was, even though it was still syncing updates from the upstream SUP/WSUS server just fine, the status messages for the SMS_WSUS_CONTROL_MANAGER component on the new SUP/WSUS box was coughing up a bunch of errors ever since I installed the roles and configured them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Management Point 500.19 CcmMessaging.log 0x87d00231</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-management-point-500.19-ccmmessaging.log-0x87d00231/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-management-point-500.19-ccmmessaging.log-0x87d00231/</guid>
      <description>My lab recently started playing up when I noticed clients weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new policies.
TDLR (it&amp;rsquo;s not even that long!): a while ago I moved my SUP/WSUS off host from the site server that also hosted a MP. As a result it seemed to have triggered this known issue: Management points stop responding to HTTP requests with error 500.19.
First port of call was CcmMessaging.log to see it was at least talking to MP OK, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get CMUnusedSources</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/get-cmunusedsources/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a PowerShell script that reports on what folders are used or unused by System Center Configuration Manager.
You can find it here on GitHub.
I demoed the script at the London Windows Manager User Group, you can watch the recording below on YouTube.
  Among a bunch of technical topics, I also learned a huge amount of valuable soft/personal things too.
Enough is enough I started writing in February and since then I have refactored the script and the idea itself many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr SQL Server Upgrade From 2012 SP4 to 2017 CU13</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-sql-server-upgrade-from-2012-sp4-to-2017-cu13/</guid>
      <description>Currently my lab&amp;rsquo;s primary site is running on 2012 R2. I recently wanted to try LEDBAT so I could sell it to a customer but it needed to be on 2016 or newer. I could have configured a 2016 &amp;ldquo;source DP&amp;rdquo; using pull distribution points and still get the experience, but then I was curious if IPU while ConfigMgr is installed was possible, turns out it is. Then I discovered I had SQL 2012 SP2 installed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpdatesDeployment.log Job Error (0x80004005)</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/updatesdeployment.log-job-error-0x80004005/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/updatesdeployment.log-job-error-0x80004005/</guid>
      <description>Glorious, 0x80004005.
No updates showing in Software Center? Is a client reporting in an unknown state in your reports?
Do you see this in UpdatesDeployment.log when triggering Software Update Deployment Evaluation Cycle?
Job error (0x80004005) received for assignment ({09985588-0eff-47e1-9f9d-3846efce8c2b}) action	Updates will not be made available Give this a whirl:
Move-Item -Path &amp;#34;$env:SystemRoot\System32\GroupPolicy\Machine\Registry.pol&amp;#34; -Destination &amp;#34;$env:SystemRoot\System32\GroupPolicy\Machine\Registry.pol.old&amp;#34; Invoke-GPUpdate -Force Verify a new Registry.pol file is created, then trigger Software Update Deployment Evaluation Cycle and Software Updates Scan Cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Throttling Distribution Point Bandwidth</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-throttling-distribution-point-bandwidth/</guid>
      <description>ℹ️ It looks like as I was writing this Microsoft have just publicly released a former internal document detailing some things that I had claimed to be undocumented (click here): Deep, deep, DEEP dive into content distribution in #SCCM by the great @vinay_pamnani Internal-only content originally, now free for public use! https://t.co/oUPTSzrTmt
&amp;mdash; Contoto Ltd. (@_contoto) February 4, 2019   In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover ways you can control bandwidth for Configuration Manager using the rate limit config available for each distribution point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Hardware Inventory Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-hardware-inventory-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated a site to 1806 and was keen to get all clients up to date too. Some machines targeted for the pre-production client were not upgrading. When I looked closer at one client I suspected client health because a hardware inventory had not been submitted in months.
Little did I know until recently, a lack of recent hardware inventory data could be a result of other things and client health is least likely to be the root cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr Database Move: Failed to Create/Backup SQL SSB Certificate</title>
      <link>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-database-move-failed-to-create/backup-sql-ssb-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamcook.io/p/configmgr-database-move-failed-to-create/backup-sql-ssb-certificate/</guid>
      <description>In a recent project I had to move the SQL database for a single primary site hierarchy to a different host in order to go beyond version 1610, because support for Windows Server 2008 R2 had ended from 1702 onward.
Everything was going smoothly up until it came to modifying the SQL configuration of the site. I was getting slapped by ConfigMgrSetup.log with:
 Create_BackupSQLCert : SQL server failed to backup cert.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
